SAMAR OMAR

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER, JUNIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER.

PROFILE

Front End web developer with a passion for learning and growing. With experience in JavaScript and React JS. As well as a junior backend developer using NodeJS and the framework NestJS. With a background in Java, Photoshop, and OOP.

I am studying Software
Engineering and aiming for a
career in web development. I
bring strong skills in team working,
fast learning, and problem solving
that help software companies in
reaching their goals in less time.
Always motivated and excited to
improve myself and my skills in
every possible way.

CONTACT

- +90 505 052 9560
- samaromm98@gmail.com
- Github
- Porfolio
- Linkedin

INFORMATION

□ Female

LANGUAGES

Arabic (Native) English (superior) Turkish (Beginner)

EDUCATION

Re:Coded Bootcamp (Re:Coded + Flatiron School) - 2020

+ Front End Web Development (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React) 5 month intense web development program run by Re:Coded with Flatiron School's curriculum.

Üsküdar University - Istanbul, Turkey (Expected 2021)

+ Bachelor's Degree: Software Engineering.

Talentvar Bootcamp - 2020

+ Back End Web Development (Mongodb, NodeJS)

2 months backend development program. Learn by directly working on the main project.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Re:Coded Labs, Istanbul, Turkey

Junior Developer Intern, 12/2019 - 5/2020

- + Worked with teams, and in pairs to build the front-end side of various projects.
- + Contributed to the teams with my knowledge of Algorithms and general programming.

Üsküdar University, Istanbul, Turkey

Teaching Assistant, 2/2020 - 4/2020

- + Work with 1st and 2st year students to help them understand algorithms and basic programming using Java, and C++.
- + Courses: Software Constructions, Introduction to Java, OOP II.

E-Bursum, Istanbul, Turkey

Junior Developer Intern, 8/2020 - present

- + Re-built the front-end side of the company's website using PHP for front-end, Sass, and Java Script without frameworks.
- + The pages I built have been integrated, sent to production, and are fully working now.
- + Received positive reactions from the clients.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

My Space - Github | Demo

This website is my own space to present my personal information!

- + Designed 4 different pages to present my info: About, CV, Projects, Contact.
- + Utilized React framework to create the project.
- + Implemented mdbootstrap library for the design.
- + Used Formspree to link the contact page with my email.

Page of Youth - Github | Demo

A planner website where you can save your schedule for each day and enter a diary/note.

- + Worked with React framework to design the front-end side.
- + Used Firebase for authentication and as a database.
- + Installed React big calendar for the homepage.

NA'AMAL - Gitlab | Demo

Website for an organization that provides remote work opportunities for refugees, by linking them to interested companies.

+ Used React framework for building front end side of pages that describe goals, and operations related to Na'amal, and how to contact them.

- + Fetched articles from Na'aml's WordPress API to build a blog for them.
- + Implemented Bootstrap library for the designs.
- + Practiced Jest for building tests of the code.

Bookmark backend - Gitlab

CRUD the user profiles of an interactive website to bookmark important YouTube videos and resources and share the knowledge with other users. (2 months group project)

- + Practiced mongodb to save the data of the users in a database.
- + Implemented NestJS to create/get/delete/update user profiles.
- + Created CRUD for Education section where the user can add their educational background.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JS, and React framework:

+ Good knowledge, have done different projects, able to create websites from scratch, or use libraries and open source.

Java:

+ Years of study, confident enough, very good knowledge of OOP in Java, able to create large scale systems.

Sass:

+Moderate knowledge, used in internship.

Photoshop:

+Moderate knowledge, editing and designing user interfaces.

NestJS and mongodb:

+ Beginner, CRUD functions.

JQuery:

+ Beginner, used in internship.